# Navi Tansaraviput

Software engineer with 9 years of experience, including 7 years in distributed systems, real-time data processing, and networking infrastructure, plus 2 years of industry and research work in ML and AI. Strong focus on reliability, scalability, and performance optimization.

**J** (+1) 000-000-0000 ■ navi@alum.mit.edu

nvtsrvp

**♦** U.S. Permanent Resident (Green Card)

### **EDUCATION**

## • Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Cambridge, MA

June 2015

#### EXPERIENCE

### • Google, Software Engineer

Google Pub/Sub is the internal messaging service that also serves as Cloud Pub/Sub backend. New York, NY, May 2022 - Present

- Led critical infrastructure improvements for exactly-once delivery, eliminating message duplication for subscriptions with previous seek requests.
- Led the in-transit data residency compliance initiative and regional endpoint service deployment to meet Personal Data Protection Law requirements, serving as the key cross-functional point of contact; designed the solution and a standardized framework, enabling new market segments while reducing future engineering effort by 75%.
- Designed and implemented auto-sharding integration for subscriber statistics requests, achieving 5x improved request affinity and 60% memory reduction. Drove multiple improvements to backlog stats staleness detection and resolution.
- Extended Checksum to Pub/Sub Storage, eliminating permanent data corruption. Resolved critical customer issues and improved data integrity.
- Mentored STEP interns and guided technical implementations for Cloud Pub/Sub to BigQuery integration with BigQuery table schema and Avro logical types schema support.

Marconi SPGW serves as the control plane functionality supporting data connections. Mountain View, CA, Jan 2019 - May 2022

- Architected voice charging data records pipeline for single and multi-bear scenarios, achieving 50% storage optimization while maintaining regulatory compliance.
- Designed real-time voice quality metrics system with dataplane sampling, improving issue detection and evaluation.
- Led Icmpv6 service framework migration from asynchronous to synchronous architecture, improving observability and reducing customer issues by 20%.
- Led operational improvements initiative: automated candidate anomaly detection, reducing 30% of weekly engineering effort, and designed experiment configuration management enabling rack-specific rollouts; created standardized procedures and knowledge-shared enabling platform-wide process improvements.

Google Health Pathology (20% Project)

Palo Alto, CA, Jun – Aug 2020

- Integrated slim ResNet ML models into cancer diagnosis pipeline using Tensorflow, implementing end-to-end testing and performance benchmarking against ResNet implemented with Keras.
- Groupon, Software Development Engineer, Fraud Detection

Palo Alto, CA, Aug 2016 - Jan 2019

- Developed real-time fraud detection platform, reducing latency by 60% through request parallelization. Onboarded three additional fraud detection signals and implemented automated prediction system in Ruby on Rails.
- Led the rearchitecture of order pending review caching system from polling to push-based, minimizing cache staleness and improving system performance.
- Developed a full-stack web application to allow the operation team to review orders manually and interact with Orders service systems in Ruby on Rails and JS.
- MIT EAPS Signals and Systems Group, Research Assistant, SLOOP Cambridge, MA, June 2015 Aug 2016
   Developed image recognition algorithms for SLOOP, a crowd-sourced animal biometrics retrieval system
- MIT CSAIL, Undergraduate researcher, Assistive Devices for Healthcare Cambridge, MA, Sep 2014 June 2015

   Developed algorithm for non-invasive vital signs monitoring and breathing anomaly detection.
- Oracle America, Inc., Software Engineering Intern, Oracle Linux

Redwood Shores, CA, June - Aug 2014

- Automated presubmit checks for kernel development version control
- Akamai Technology, Inc., Engineering Intern, Platform Operation Cambridge, MA, June Aug 2012

  O Developed web app for log analysis and visualization using HTML/CSS/JS frontend and Python/PostgreSQL backend.

#### SKILLS & ACTIVITIES

- Languages: C++20, Python3, Shell Scripting (bash, zsh), SQL, Ruby on Rails, Java, JavaScript/Typescript, HTML, CSS
- Microsoft TEALS Program Instructor, Millennium High School, New York, NY, Sep 2024 Present: Teaching Introduction to Computer Science to a class of 23 high school students.